Finding aid for the Xavier University Department of Nursing records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Department of Nursing records
1970-2015
1970-1997
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Department of Nursing
2.5 linear feet (5 boxes)
This is a collection of various documents stemming from the activity of the Nursing Department at Xavier University and also previously at Edgecliff College.
XUA-74
History of Xavier University Department of Nursing
The Xavier University Department of Nursing came to the Xavier campus after the purchase of Edgecliff College from the Sisters of Mercy in 1983 and the subsequent sale of the Edgecliff campus in 1987. Originally in Xavier's College of Professional Studies this Department now resides in Xavier's College of Social Sciences, Health & Education.
Scope and Content
The materials in this collection consist chiefly in departmental minutes, correspondence, reports, self-studies, and proposals.
Statement of Arrangement
Materials in this collection are arranged by general series:
Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports
Brochures
Studies and Proposals
Recent Program Developments
Related Material
See also XUA-37, Edgecliff College records for limited additional information about the Nursing Department while at Edgecliff College.
Restrictions on Access
Some materials may have restricted access. Please contact the archives staff.
Accruals
Additions to this collection are expected.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Nursing-- Study and teaching
Organizations/Corporations:
Edgecliff College. Department of Nursing
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports, 1970-1991
  - Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports, 1988 January-July (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Brochures, 1997-2006; undated
  - Brochures and Announcements, 1997-2006; undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Studies and Proposals, 1975-1997
  - Feasibility Study for Bachelor's Program in Nursing, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Departmental Self-Study, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Departmental Self Study Supplement, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Bachelor's Degree Program Progress Report, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bachelor's Degree Program Progress Report Supplement, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - BSN Program Review, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Proposed Associate Degree Program in Nursing, 1988 April (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Master of Science in Nursing: Program Proposal, 1990 September (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Master of Science in Nursing Program Proposal, 1990 September (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Xavier University / Deaconess Hospital Associate Degree Program Self Study, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Xavier University / Deaconess Hospital Associate Degree Program Appendix, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Application for Entry-Level Bachelor's Program, 1995 March (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - BSN Program / National League for Nursing Self Study, 1997 April (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Recent Program Developments, 2014
  - Doctor of Nursing Practice 2014 Program Start, 2015 April 22 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    This folder contains an email with an attachment that gives information on the new Doctor of Nursing Practice program at Xavier University.